Finding Aid for the Terrence O'Flaherty Papers PASC.0026
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Promotional Material, 1960s-1970s
  - Invitations, (undated) (Box 319, Folder 11)
    Mobil Masterpiece Theatre and Mystery screening party and NBC dinner party.
  - KGO-TV ABC-TV Preview Review Invitation, (1964) (Box 305, Folder 3)
  - KPIX Channel 5 San Francisco press releases, (undated) (Box 299, Folder 12)
  - Les Miserables fold-out CBS advertisement, (1978) (Box 305, Folder 9)
  - NBC press releases, (ca. 1980) (Box 303)
    2 folders.
  - NET-PBS '70 press kit, (ca. 1970) (Box 306, Folder 4)
    Transcripts, press releases, stills, and correspondence pertaining to National Educational Television, the Public Broadcasting System, and KQED San Francisco.
  - Notes accompanying promotional items for Alfred Hitchcock Presents, Captains Courageous, and The Clowns., (1977, 1985) (Box 319, Folder 7)
  - PBS The Nutcracker illustration; CBS Playhouse: My Father and My Mother program; Images in Time and Space exhibit press kit., (ca. 1988-1989) (Box 324, Folder 1)
    Found loose with ABC stills.
  - Television episode announcements, (1979, 1984) (Box 319, Folder 12)
    Barry Manilow Special and Capitol.
  - Wizard of Oz (NBC advertisement), (undated) (Box 305, Folder 8)
- Script material, 1957-1987, bulk dates 1963-1985; 1963-1985
  The series includes script materials that appear to have been sent to O'Flaherty to promote television programs or for his comment. The majority of items represent news shows and documentaries.
  Items are organized alphabetically by title.
  - 60 Minutes: Recall the Mayor - script material, (1983 Apr 24) (Box 298, Folder 2)
  - ABC News Closeup: Oh, Tell the World What Happened script material, (c. 1982) (Box 298, Folder 1)
  - Adam to Atom script material, (1962) (Box 296, Folder 2)
    With Charlie Chucklecough Presents.
  - As Life Begins script material, (1975 Dec 17) (Box 299, Folder 15)
  - Brand New Illustrated Journal of the Arts (The) script material, (1982 Jan 1) (Box 296, Folder 5)
  - Broken Arrow - Complaint to the National News Council report, (1982 Mar 31) (Box 298, Folder 3)
  - Cable Cars: San Francisco, Of Course! script material, (c. 1980) (Box 297, Folder 8)
  - CBS News Special - Juilliard and Beyond: A Life in Music script material, (1982 July 24) (Box 299, Folder 7)
  - CBS News: On the Road with Charles Kuralt Czechoslovackia, (1983 June 28) (Box 299, Folder 2)
  - CBS Reports - Terrorism: War in the Shadows script material, (1984 June 19) (Box 296, Folder 12)
  - CBS Reports: After the Dream Comes True script material, (1982 Aug 4) (Box 299, Folder 1)
  - CBS Reports: Don't Touch That Dial! script material, (1982 Dec 23) (Box 298, Folder 5)
  - CBS Reports: Guatemala script material, (1982 Aug 20) (Box 297, Folder 11)
  - CBS Reports: The Plane that Fell From the Sky script material, (1983 June 29) (Box 299, Folder 3)
  - CBS Reports: The Vanishing Family - Crisis in Black America script material, (1986 Jan 25) (Box 297, Folder 1)
  - Charlie Chucklecough Presents script material, (1962) (Box 296, Folder 2)
    With Adam to Atom
  - Chrysler Theatre: Something About Lee Wiley script material, (1963) (Box 299, Folder 8)
  - Con Man (The) script material, (1957 Dec 11) (Box 296, Folder 4)
    With novel.
  - Czechoslovakia, the Wayward Satellite script material, (1968) (Box 299, Folder 9)
  - David Brinkley Journal Special: Our Man In Andorra, Monaco, San Marino, Liechtenstein - and Smom script material, (1962 Jan 28) (Box 298, Folder 11)
  - Day After Trinity (The): J. Robert Oppenheimer and the Atomic Bomb script material, (undated) (Box 297, Folder 2)
  - Do You Remember Love script material, (1985 May 21) (Box 296, Folder 9)
  - Earthquake: Terror and Trauma script material, (undated) (Box 307, Folder 14)
  - Freedom to Speak #5: The Hawks and the Doves script material, (undated) (Box 298, Folder 4)
  - Gibbsville: All the Young Girls script material, (1976 July 27) (Box 298, Folder 12)
  - Hawaiians (The) script material, (undated) (Box 297, Folder 9)
  - How Life Begins: A 3M Special script material, (1968) (Box 299, Folder 6)
  - Intimate Writings of Theodor Hammer (The) script material, (undated) (Box 298, Folder 9)
  - March 4th, 1933, (1983 Feb 24) (Box 298, Folder 10)
  - Mitzi...The First Time script material, (1973) (Box 299, Folder 17)
  - Murder at Nha Trang script material, (1987 May 1) (Box 298, Folder 7)
  - New Land (The) - The Word Is Growth script material, (1974 June 27) (Box 296, Folder 6)
  - Not Here by Cap Weinberger, Jr. script material, (undated) (Box 307, Folder 13)
  - Our Times with Bill Moyers: Divorce script material, (undated) (Box 299, Folder 4)
  - Outline - treatment for a film on Australia for Intertel script material, (1963 June) (Box 296, Folder 7)
  - Plutonium Connection (The) script material, (1975 Mar 9) (Box 299, Folder 16)
  - President of the Sky (The) - proposal, (undated) (Box 297, Folder 4)
  - Princess Bow Wow script material, (undated) (Box 298, Folder 6)
  - Program schedules, (1985) (Box 297, Folder 7)
    NBC and KRON-TV
  - Quest (The): The Buffalo Hunters script material, (1976 July 14) (Box 297, Folder 5)
  - Red China: Year of the Gun? script material, (1966 Apr 21) (Box 297, Folder 10)
  - Something They Are Stammering Leaves Me Dying script material, (1964) (Box 299, Folder 10)
  - Tales from the Vatican Collections script material, (1983 Nov 16) (Box 296, Folder 10)
  - Television's Vietnam: The Real Story script material, (1985 May 24) (Box 297, Folder 6)
  - Undersea World of Jacques Cousteau (The): The Sea Birds of Isabella script material, (1975 Dec 8) (Box 299, Folder 11)
  - Undersea World of Jacques Cousteau (The): Tragedy of the Red Salmon script material, (1970 Nov 24) (Box 297, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified script pages, (undated) (Box 296, Folder 3)
  - Untitled script, (undated) (Box 296, Folder 1)
    With Big Screen China article
  - Vibrations for a New People: A conversation with Angela Davis script material, (1972 Feb 7) (Box 299, Folder 14)
  - Whiz Kids: The Network script material, (1983 Nov 21) (Box 296, Folder 11)
  - Who Will Love My Children script material, (1983 Feb 14) (Box 296, Folder 8)
  - Woman He Loved (The) script material, (1987 Nov 19) (Box 298, Folder 8)
- Publications, mid-1950s-1971, 1988
  The series includes books and a small number research reports, periodicals, books, and other publications collected by O'Flaherty. The publications cover the history, development, economics, sociology and technology of television. Some of the books are signed or contain personal notes to O'Flaherty; some books may contain additional news release or promotional material in the item.
  The series is arranged in a loose alphabetical order by publication title.
  - Better Radio and Television newsletter, (1965) (Box 306, Folder 13)
  - Fair Trial vs. a Free Press, an occasional paper on the free society published by the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, (1965 Oct 14) (Box 306, Folder 14)
  - Guide to Films on Urban America (A), (undated) (Box 305, Folder 2)
  - Hollywood Reporter - 2 volumes, (1963) (Box 305, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals, (c. 1958-59, 1961-62, 1967-68) (Box 304, Folder 1)
    Who's Who in Television (2 volumes), TV Preview
  - Periodicals, (1956, 1960-61, 1976, 1988) (Box 306, Folder 1)
    TV Star Annual, Who's Who In Television, American Film, and Cable View Magazine
  - Playbill magazine theatre programs (3 items), (1966) (Box 315, Folder 19)
  - Primetime (published booklet of television-related cartoons from the New Yorker), (c. 1971) (Box 315, Folder 20)
  - Printed sheet Music (folder 1 of 2), (undated) (Box 304, Folder 5)
    With a copy of Lady of the House inscribed to O'Flaherty by composers Mike Crandall and Minco de Bruin.
  - Printed sheet Music (folder 2 of 2) (Box 304, Folder 6)
  - Reproductions of the Bill of Rights, Declaration of Independence, and the Constitution with souvenir sleeve., (undated) (Box 319, Folder 6)
  - Summary of the major findings in The First Year of Sesame Street: An Evaluation (A) - by Samuel Ball and Gerry Ann Bogatz, published by Educational Testing Service., (1970 Oct) (Box 306, Folder 16)
  - Television for the Family: A Comprehensive Guide to Family Viewing, (c. 1967) (Box 306, Folder 6)
  - Television: A Perspective on Tomorrow, address given by Julian Goodman, president of NBC, to the Association of National Advertisers, (undated) (Box 305, Folder 10)
  - Transcript of Extemporaneous Remarks by FCC Commissioner Nicholas Johnson, published by the National Citizens Committee for Broadacasting, (1969 Nov 10) (Box 306, Folder 15)
  - Violence in television programming, published by the Commision on Research and Social Action of the American Lutheran Church., (1969 Nov) (Box 306, Folder 3)
- Sound recordings, undated
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  The small number of sound recordings were produced to promote particular television programs, and distributed to media professionals, critics, and journalists, and for the most part were unavailable to the general public.
  - Assorted records, (undated) (Box 330)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
    Marlene Dietrich I, Unverganlich Unvergessen; Music from the Gene Austin Story; Perry Como, I Concentrate on You; Noel and Gertie; Noel and Gertie and Bea; Sail Away (Original Broadway Cast); A Knightrider Christmas (Kitt the Amazing Car of tomorrow).
  - Voices of the Deep sound recording featuring Jacques Cousteau, (undated) (Box 319, Folder 10)
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Voices of the Deep: New Oceanology Teaching Aid for the Secondary Schools, undated; pasc_026_319_010a; Columbia Special Products; 1 sound recordings (1 flex disc; Duration: 0:08:27) (Box 319, Case 10)
      CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
      Scope and Contents
      Content note: features the voices of Jacques Yves Cousteau and Dr. William N. Tavolga
    - Voices of the Deep: New Oceanology Teaching Aid for the Secondary Schools, undated; pasc_026_319_010b; Columbia Special Products; 1 sound recordings (1 flex disc; Duration: 0:08:18) (Box 319, Case 10)